WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Did you sleep well? Very.
It hasn't taken me long to get used
to sharing a bed again.
Who is it? Breakfast, madam.
One moment.
Ah. Thank you so much.
I can manage.
Have you ordered something
for yourself? You can't have mine.
It'll be here any second.
You've worked up a good appetite.
I can't bear vulgar jokes.
I'll make note of that. I've made
note of everything.
How you look in the morning. How you
dress.
How you put on your make-up.
Why particularly?
Because I want to acclimate myself
with the routines and rituals that
will govern the rest of my life.
Are you governed by ritual and
routine?
I don't think I am. Do you really
have to leave today?
I'm afraid so.
Surely there are delights
in Liverpool we have yet to share.
We've driven round Cheshire and
dined in public for almost a week.
By some miracle, we have managed to
get away with it.
Let's not push our luck.
Does it matter if we get found out?
We're gonna be down the aisle before
you can say, "Jack Robinson." No.
And yes, it does matter.
I've been tarnished once and I won't
be tarnished again.
Nothing is going to happen that
isn't properly announced
organised and executed.
Isn't that your breakfast?
Miss Bunting says I've quite a gift
for it now I've got started.
I left school when I were 11.
What were I supposed to learn by
then?
If I were at school now, I'd be
there at least till I were 14.
What's the matter?
Sorry, love. What were you saying?
Nothing.
Before he left, Mr Bricker said he
wants to show us the della Francescas
in the National Gallery when we're
next in London.
You go. Actually, I wouldn't mind
knowing if ours is any good.
We don't often see you for
breakfast.
We've got a meeting to organise the
church flowers.
The rota seems to have gone wrong.
Is Mary back today?
Supposed to be. Good. We've been
sent a proposition from a man in Leeds.
What's that? Let's wait till Mary
gets home then we can talk about it.
Do you have any plans? I may walk
down to Yew Tree Farm.
I'll give you a lift if you like.
Has Rose left? I think so.
She planned to get an early train to
York.
She wanted to spend the day with her
Russians which is nice.
Are you ready to go?
Edith is getting so fond of that
little girl.
I only hope she isn't driving
the mother mad.
Mr Carson, please may I make a
telephone call?
Don't make it a habit.
I'm sorry to ask but I wonder if I
might be alone.
If you wish.
Hello. I've read your advertisement
in the London Magazine.
Choose Your Own Path.
This is me. We'll talk soon.
We're settled now. We just have to
get organised.
Oh, what is the latest
from your ageing Romeo?
If it's of interest, I haven't heard
anything from him
since you and I last met.
Oh, how disappointing.
To you, perhaps.
Not especially to me.
By the way, how is Spratt?
He's well, I think. Why do you ask?
He wasn't there to open the door. I
wondered if he might be ill.
Oh, no. He's not ill. He's in
Liverpool.
His niece got married yesterday
and Spratt had to take her down the
aisle. Oh.
It seems unlikely to think of Spratt
with a private life.
Hm. Yes. Unlikely and extremely
inconvenient.
But you can't begrudge him that.
Servants are human beings too.
Yes. But preferably only on their
days off.
So they want to take this witness
business further?
I'm afraid so. It's a young woman,
apparently.
She was on her way to meet a friend
by the Statue of Eros in Piccadilly.
Now, she swears she heard Green
speak as she walked by.
There was clatter from traffic but
she heard him say,
"Why have you come?"
Who was he talking to? She couldn't
see.
She was quite short and behind his
back. She looked up when he spoke
but it was only to see him fall into
the road. She kept quiet.
Well, it was in the paper and they
said it was an accident.
But that phrase haunted her. "Why
have you come?"
Till she felt she had to report it.
I still don't see what brings you here.
Green complained of a quarrel
while he was staying at Downton.
He felt badly treated, was angry
about it and...
he told Lord Gillingham's other
servants. Why didn't they report it?
Because everyone thought his death
was an accident.
Until now.
I'm sorry but as I remember, he was
in high spirits while he was here.
Rather too high, if you get my
meaning.
He had the maids and footmen playing
Racing Demon
and screaming the house down.
So you had no reason to believe he
fell out with anyone? None at all.
He was rather a bumptious type
but if anyone objected to that,
it was me.
Isobel was asking about your
travels.
She's coming for dinner this evening
so you can tell her yourself.
Another cup of tea, M'Lord?
Thank you, no.
You can show her your sketches.
Where are they anyway?
Can't we see them? Now that you're
back,
a building company has been in
touch.
They want to put up 50 houses. 50?
Modest ones. He's got his eye on
Pip's Corner.
He wants to widen the lane to the
green
to access the village centre.
They want to buy Pip's Corner?
They want to build on Pip's Corner.
We take a percentage of sales.
It's a good offer. I won't have 50
ugly modern houses
built over a field of mine.
Well, we don't have to make a
decision now.
Hello, darling. Hello, Sybbie. Now,
let's go and sit by the fire.
We want to hear all about your...
The police must have muddled Downton
with some other place. I expect so.
You don't remember any bad feeling
involving Mr Green, do you? No.
Well, better get moving. They'll be
down in a minute.
Oh, Mr Carson. There's a telephone
call for Mr Barrow.
Go and find him, Mr Molesley, seeing
as you're the First Footman now.
Are you free for a moment?
I've not got long.
No, well, it won't take long.
I've had a letter from my sister.
The mother of my nephew Archie.
He was shot, wasn't he, poor boy.
Yes. He was shot. For cowardice.
His parents live in Farsley near
Leeds.
Now, the Farsley people are putting
up their own memorial like we are.
That's nice. Well, it is and it
isn't.
You see, the locals only know that
Archie died in the War.
They'll expect to see his name among
the rest. Yes.
But the committee won't put him on
the list.
He's... He's not worthy.
Apparently. So says the War Office.
I am sorry. That must be terribly
upsetting for her.
Well, it brings it back for us, you
see.
It brings it back
and makes his death nothing at all.
I wish I could do something. Well, I
did just wonder...
I mean, if she were able to say he'd
been included in our memorial,
because of a family connection,
no-one would wonder
why he was missing from the one in
Farsley.
Have you spoken to Mr Carson? No.
I was hoping you might do that.
Me? Well, everyone knows you can
twist him around your little finger.
Then, EVERYONE is wrong.
Well, will you have a go, please?
We're about to start
the Hollandaise.
So we've got time if it curdles.
Right. I'm coming.
Please.
I hope you're not too tired after
your exertions.
Ooh, M'Lady. I'm not tired exactly.
Oh, good. I'm glad if the wedding was
a success.
Oh. The wedding was a success.
Yes.
Spratt, I have told you before, I do
not appreciate a man of mystery.
If you have something to say, say
it.
I would, Your Ladyship, but it may
not be quite right for me to tell.
Well, if that is the case then do NOT
say it.
Do you have some other business?
Only that it may not be mine to
tell,
but it is, in a way, yours.
You're testing me, Spratt.
And I warn you, being tested does
not bring out the best in me.
No, Your Ladyship. I will not repeat
myself.
Either impart this piece of
information,
if you can empower yourself
to do so,
or go.
Very well.
I hope Lady Mary enjoyed her time in
Liverpool.
What? I was standing outside the
Grand Hotel this morning, M'Lady,
when I saw her come out with her
suitcases.
She was accompanied by Lord
Gillingham
who had clearly also been staying in
the hotel.
Well, yes. They were both staying
there.
They were attending an informal
conference of northern landowners.
Lord Gillingham thought Lady Mary
might derive benefit from it.
So you knew about it?
Of course I did.
Why?
What do you imagine you were
witnessing?
Well... Nothing vulgar, I hope!
Nothing beneath the dignity of a
butler of this house.
Oh. Nothing... of... that... sort,
M'Lady.
I'm glad to hear it.
Now, if you'll be good enough to let
me drink my brandy in peace.
You don't think Mr Bates ever knew
it was Mr Green, do you?
What are you asking me for?
I don't know anything you don't
know.
Anyway, Mr Carson wasn't impressed
by the sound of the witness.
But they could make out he was
in London that day, couldn't they?
He left at dawn. He was back late.
They'll say he could have managed
it.
Even if Mr Bates was in London, we
have no reason to suppose
he had anything to do with it. What
do you mean, 'even if he was'?
Do you think he was? I don't know if
he was there or not.
Why would I if you don't?
They'll find out.
About Mr Green.
They'll find out what he did.
How?
There's no-one in this house knows,
except you, me and Lady Mary.
And she won't give it away.
No, I don't think she will. There
you are, then.
But they'll find out somehow.
Of course you must bring them. If
you want to.
They do so love an excursion.
It'll be fun. I'll come and help.
What are you going to do in London?
I have a fitting with Monsieur
Molyneux. He's over from Paris.
The Dowager Lady Grantham is on the
telephone for you, M'Lady. Thank you.
Will you stay at Rosamund's?
If she'll have me.
Robert, any chance you could come
to? I'm afraid I can't.
I've a dreary meeting all afternoon.
What about you, Edith? I'm taking Mr
Bricker up on his offer
to show me the National Gallery.
I'm watching little Marigold.
Mrs Drewe is taking the youngest boy
to the dentist.
Can't someone else step in? I said
I'd do it. Rose.
We're taking my Russians to Howarth
where the Brontes lived.
What will they make of the Brontes?
Good things surely.
Hopeless lovers wandering over a
desolate moor.
If it wasn't Emily Bronte, it could
be Tolstoy or Gogol.
That's why I want to bring them to
Downton.
They can compare the old Chekhovian
vie de chateau
with the way the English do it.
Won't that make them unhappy?
A little nostalgic maybe but they
seem to enjoy that.
We have some Russian things here from
when Papa and Mama went in 1874.
I shall look them out. What did your
grandmother want?
She wondered if I'll have time to
look in tomorrow. That's all.
I hope your flurry of telephonic
communication
does not involve bad news, Mr
Barrow.
My father's ill, Mr Carson.
Oh, I am sorry.
Will you need time off?
Well, I ought to leave in the
morning.
Really? If you want me to see him
alive. Oh, my heaven.
Of course I do.
Of course you must go.
I'm sorry to hear it.
I remember your father very well.
Don't pretend. You couldn't care
less.
I've known your family for a good
long time.
I may not want to be your spy but
nothing changes that.
If you say so. Your dad was always
kind to me. Was he?
Because he was never very kind to
me.
You're quiet. Am I? I don't mean to
be.
I was thinking we might get out for
a night when we're due time off.
Somewhere peaceful. Away from here.
Do you ever wonder what it would be
like to go
to a place where no-one knows us?
And just start again. Why do you say
that?
I'm being stupid.
That's why.
I hear you're getting on well with
your mathematics, Daisy.
An extra feather in your cap.
Yes, it is.
But now I wonder... You wonder what?
Well, should I stop there?
That's enough, Daisy. Come and carry
the spotted dick.
Good night, Baxter.
M'Lady, I hope you don't mind but I
would like to know
whether I'm staying or going.
You're right. I have made you wait
an unreasonable time.
I just feel I need to plan if you've
come to a decision.
I have. I think I have.
Tomorrow I want you tell me
the missing element of your story.
If you do, I'll give you a decision.
Is everything planned for the trip?
It is.
I'm looking forward to it. Really?
I'm afraid I find those journeys a
slog these days.
Do you ever think of the War?
What do you mean?
How it was. When the girls were
working with the officers
and I was running everything with
Barrow.
I don't remember Mary doing much.
Sometimes I find myself thinking how
busy we were. How useful.
You can't wish those days back again.
Well...
..I wouldn't admit it outside this
room.
What was that business about
building houses at Pip's Corner?
Nothing to trouble you with.
So you had fun? Don't ask me to
elaborate.
Have you set the date?
For the wedding, M'Lady.
No. He's not trying to get out of it?
No.
But there's no hurry. We don't have
to rush into it.
By the way, would you do me
the greatest possible favour?
I will if I can. Would you hide this
in the cottage?
You mean the thing. Well, I can't
leave it here.
Suppose Mrs Hughes found it. Or
Edith. Or Mama.
Please take it. And the book.
There must be a corner cupboard
in the cottage where no-one goes.
Very well, M'Lady. Thank you.
But I do feel I'm aiding and
abetting a sin.
I just hope I won't be made to pay.
I gather the local bobby was here
today.
Carson said a witness had turned
up who'd seen that man die.
But wasn't it a crowded pavement?
Surely there were hundreds of them.
This one says she heard Mr Green
talking just before he fell.
Sergeant Willis was asking if he'd
quarrelled with anyone
when he was at Downton. Why?
Mr Green had told the people he
worked with
that he'd been treated badly while
he was here.
HE was treated badly?! I know.
But...
..we have to be on our guard.
I mean, I'm sure Mr Bates never knew
it was him
but if they find out what Mr Green
did, then...
There can't be any evidence against
Bates. They'd have found it by now.
What are you doing?
Nothing. Is this some mysterious
present for me?
No, it's something of Lady Mary's.
What is it?
That's private. For her.
Then why has she given it to you?
She wants me to keep it.
Why are you putting me off?
I'm not doing any such thing.
Add the name of a coward to our
memorial?
Are you quite well?
Mr Carson, surely by now we know
enough about shellshock
to be more understanding than
we were at the start of the War.
Look, I don't mean to sound cruel but
the lad was troubled
and off his head for all we know.
I'm sorry for him. I'm sorry for his
family and for Mrs Patmore.
Well, then. But is it fair to the
millions of men
who stood by their posts up to their
waists in mud,
terrified out of their wits
yet determined to do their best
for King and country? What do you
mean?
Is it fair to say to them,
"Your sacrifice weighs just the same
as the man who abandoned his duty
and ran for it"?
I... I'm sorry, Mrs Hughes, but I
don't think it's right
to make so little of the gift those
young men gave us when they died.
I see.
I hoped I'd catch you before we go.
Oh, yes?
She's given me an ultimatum.
What's she said? I must either tell
her the rest of my story or leave.
And if you do tell her, does that
mean you can stay?
She wouldn't commit herself.
So what will you do? I don't know.
There is a story, and maybe she has
a right to hear it.
But once it's told, I want it back
in the ground and buried.
Then make that your condition. What?
She's made conditions so can you.
The worst that can happen
is that she refuses and you go.
Which will happen anyway if you say
nothing. Oh.
You don't think he'll relent?
I'm afraid not.
I just wanted to be sure you knew
there'll only be four for dinner.
She's told you, then.
I have. They'd never have allowed
it.
Is that so? But I don't want you to
think I'm unsympathetic.
Yes, well... Sympathy butters no
parsnips.
I'd better get on.
What's the matter with her?
She's had bad news.
Oh, by the way, Mr Carson...
Yes, Daisy.
..you wouldn't mind if I were to sit
an examination, would you?
Not now. But when I'm ready.
That's a question for Mrs Patmore
or Mrs Hughes. But you don't object?
Well, since you ask, I'm not
convinced any of this extra work
is necessary for your place in the
scheme of things.
Mr Carson, Sergeant Willis is here.
Hm.
My advice Daisy is to go as far in
life as God and luck allow.
Are you sure about this? I'm never
convinced surprises
are all they're cracked up to be.
Don't be silly.
I'll give her a treat.
I thought we might go dancing.
I hear the new band at Claridge's is
marvellous.
Does Aunt Rosamund know you're
coming? I'll tell her when I arrive.
They were just going to have supper
together and go to bed. Bates.
Mr Carson said you were looking for
me, M'Lord.
My meeting's been cancelled.
I've decided to run up to London.
Would you make up a bag for me?
Black tie not white.
Would you like me to come with you?
No need. I'll be back tomorrow.
Mr Bates? Well, that's it. He didn't
like Mr Bates. Not at all.
And we know now that he said so to
Lord Gillingham's butler.
Well, I don't remember that.
He mentioned Mr Bates by name?
He called him 'the valet' and there
isn't another, is there?
Not now. You do surprise me.
Mr Bates keeps himself to himself.
You won't mind if I talk to him?
Not at all. Be my guest.
You can take a seat and I'll send
for him.
Thank you, Spratt.
I trust you enjoyed your stay in
Liverpool, M'Lady?
You found it extremely interesting,
didn't you, dear?
Yes, I did.
I think we'll have some tea. Thank
you, Spratt.
Very good, Your Ladyship.
Obviously, it's very shocking
to someone of your generation.
Don't let us hide behind the changing
times, my dear.
This is shocking to most people in
1924. Yes.
Can we be confident that there will
be no unwanted epilogue?
You can be quite sure.
Well, I must say that makes a nice...
A nice what?
A nice kettle of fish.
Is there any chance of a proposal?
Every chance.
He already has.
He wants to set the date.
Oh. Oh, I see.
Well, I'm not saying I approve
because I don't.
But it does put things in rather a
different light.
Yes.
When will you announce it?
I'm not sure. We haven't decided.
Then you'd better get on with it.
If I was seduced by a man,
I would not let any grass grow
under his feet
if he'd offered to do the decent
thing. I wasn't seduced, Granny.
A young woman of good family who
finds herself in the bed
of a man who is not her husband has
invariably been seduced.
She couldn't have gone to bed with
him of her own free will?
NOT if she was the daughter of an
Earl.
Oh, there you are, Spratt.
Lady Mary's been telling me all
about her conference.
I hope you found it interesting,
M'Lady.
I learned a great deal that I never
knew before.
Thank you, Spratt.
You've had the journey to think
about, Baxter,
and I accept your condition. We have
time.
I don't have to be anywhere till
later.
At the house in Ovington Square,
there was a footman.
His name was Coyle. Peter Coyle.
He was very handsome and after a
while,
I could do nothing but by his
permission.
He was a cruel man although I
couldn't see it then.
At least...
..I could see it, really.
He was nasty. And he made me nasty.
And I embraced it.
Tell me about the robbery.
He handed in his notice and on his
last night, I took the jewels.
He wanted them all but I only took
some.
And you gave them to him and he
left.
He said where to meet him the next
day and I thought he'd be there.
But he never came. I never saw him
after. He got clean away.
And you took the blame but why?
I was ashamed.
I'd let him change me. I'd abandoned
everything I believed
to please a worthless man.
Surely if you told the police now...
No, M'Lady.
I won't bring it back to life. Leave
him be.
As it is, he'll never know a day's
happiness
for there is nothing good in him.
So what might you have done in York
that would place you there?
Now, let me think. I posted a letter
to an old army pal.
Would he still have it? That I
couldn't tell you.
Anything else? I made enquiries at a
shoe shop.
Do you recall which one? Browns.
In Queen Street.
They were opening up. Then I had
a cup of coffee at the Royal York.
I went back there for a drink later
on before I caught the train home.
In the middle of the day?
I walked around. I had a sandwich at
lunchtime in some pub or other.
Let me think.
Don't worry. I've got enough. Thank
you for your time.
No need to frown, Mrs Bates. Just
routine.
But why would Mr Green say such
things about Mr Bates?
Who knows? Anyway, everything seems
to be in order.
Good day to you.
I don't know why Mr Green would want
to make trouble for you.
Well, I never liked him so I suppose
he never liked me.
Yes, but to invent a quarrel then
tell the world about it.
It's as if he were expecting me to
make trouble first
and so he was covering himself in
case I did.
It does seem like that, doesn't it?
I have to get a mark out of His
Lordship's tails. Go.
Of course. You go.
Every figure shows a different kind
of reverence.
Some eager, some contemplative.
Some amazed.
Even the magpie seems to have been
struck dumb.
You're very sharp.
Umbria was full of magpies
so della Francesca chose a bird known
for its chatter
and made it silent in wonder.
How beautiful it is.
I think your picture may be a study
for this angel.
There are elements common to both.
It was painted at the end of his
life.
I envy him.
To be able to create something like
this when death was closing in.
I'd love to think I could still do
something
that people talk about more than
four centuries later.
You don't sound confident.
I doubt they'll remember anything
I've done by the time my body's cold.
I'm sure that's not true. You're not
but I like you for saying it.
Come and look at this one.
I'm afraid I'm taking up far too
much of your time.
Not true. I'm enjoying myself.
M'Lady.
M'Lady?!
Are you there?
M'Lady?
Wait here. Wait here.
I didn't know where you were.
Oh, you're back. She's been no
trouble at all.
She should have gone when Tim got
home, M'Lady.
I was enjoying myself. That's very
kind, I'm sure.
Hey. Hello.
Well, I suppose I should be off.
Unless you'd like me to stay while
you settle Billy.
That's generous, M'Lady but there's
no need. Good.
Right. I'll be off then.
Can I look in tomorrow?
You must be so busy.
Why don't I come and then you can
turn me out if you like.
Goodbye, darling.
Bye. Bye.
Honestly, Tim!
She'll hear you. Let her get away.
I can't manage it much longer.
I'm sorry if she's lonely and
wants a child
but she can't have ours. You're not
being reasonable.
Just now, I thought she'd taken her.
I did, truly. I wish we'd never
started it.
Think what she could do for the girl
if she's a mind to.
In 10 years or 15. Are we all to live
together in a threesome until then?
Is that what you want? Me?
I thought she was soft on you
but it's the other way round.
You're the one who's soft. Soft in
the head!
She keeps being engaged. I wonder if
there's a fault on the line?
I'll send a telegram. I don't know.
I probably should go back.
I'm in quite the wrong clothes for
dinner. Please.
You said yourself she wouldn't mind.
As for your clothes, you'll be the
best-looking woman
in the Ritz dining room whatever
you're wearing. Oh, golly.
That's cheered me up. I mean it.
I so want to hear what you have to
say about it.
I can't think why. I don't know
anything. Nonsense.
You have an instinct for the key
elements of every picture.
They speak to you. I envy that.
Well, I probably shouldn't but I
guess I will.
I won't stay out late, though.
Don't worry.
You'll be home and safe as the clock
strikes 12.
A lot sooner than that, please.
But surely if Bates convinced Willis
he was in York that day...
I only said it may not be over.
Why not?
The sergeant's a nice man but he's
not the brightest button in the box.
According to Mr Carson, Mr Bates
told the Sergeant
he visited a shoe shop as it was
opening.
The shoe shop is in Queen Street,
10 minutes walk from the station.
Oh. He also had a cup of coffee at
the Royal York
which operates as a station hotel.
You mean he still had time to get to
London and back?
Do you think Carson registered any
of this? I doubt it.
And he wouldn't give Mr Bates away
if he did.
But there's a danger that Sergeant
Willis or someone he talks to
may put two and two together. They'd
still have to prove it.
Yes, they would still need proof.
Let's keep a hold of that.
I had such a nice evening.
Me too. I love London.
Sometimes I forget how much but I
do.
I remember when I first arrived.
You don't want to hear about all
that. But I do.
London scared me at first.
I'd only been in a school room a few
months before.
But my mother was eager.
Why especially?
We weren't really in the first rank
in Cincinnati.
Still less when we moved to New
York.
My father was Jewish and the money
was new.
But there was a lot of it and I was
pretty.
I suppose I can say that now I'm an
old lady.
She thought you'd make a better match
over the Atlantic.
And suddenly, here I was in these
vast ballrooms.
And all the other girls seemed
to know what to do and what to wear.
And how to flirt. I bet you were
more beautiful than all of them.
More original. More real.
I certainly got a lot of
names on my dance card.
Listen to me bragging.
Please forgive me. I never talk
about myself.
Why did I say all that? Because I'm
interested.
Well, it's time for me to stop.
We're nearly there.
Can't we pretend we're not? And walk
round the square again?
The truth is, I am quite
light-headed.
Going out for a night on the town.
Seems more my daughters' territory
than my own.
You can't know what a good time I
had.
Please may we do it again.
I doubt it.
But I hear the offer as a
compliment.
Rosamund.
I hope you got my cable.
But I've had such a... Such a what?
..nice time. Robert!
I didn't know you were coming up
to London. You never gave me a clue!
It was meant to be a surprise. I got
a table at Claridge's
so we could make a night of it.
I am sorry.
Shall we telephone? Don't worry. I
cancelled everything
when we got Mr Bricker's telegram.
Where's Rosamund? Upstairs. She gave
me your dinner and went to bed.
I'm dreadfully sorry. So you said.
Wait a minute. I don't see I've done
anything to make you angry.
No? I travel to London in order to
give my wife a treat
only to find she's out dining with
another man.
Mr Bricker wanted to discuss the
paintings.
Rosamund said she needed an early
night.
Why was it so wrong to accept his
invitation?
Bricker was interested in discussing
the pictures with you?
Yes. Is that so difficult to
believe?
That an art expert would find your
observations on the work
of Piero della Francesca impossible
to resist? Yes.
It IS hard to believe. I'm going to
bed.
Cora. It's quite all right.
You've said what you think
and you've every right to do so.
Tell me, does Edith seem very
distracted to you?
I'm not sure I'd notice. Well, she
does to me.
As if she were always thinking about
something else.
I might say the same of you. It can
be hard to know what to do for the best.
You don't want to hurt people but
you may have to.
I know what you mean.
Sorry. That just slipped out.
Are you talking about Tony?
Maybe.
I don't know. I'm not sure.
I was beginning to think you'd
settled on him. I had. I think.
But now, I seem to have unsettled.
Goodness! I haven't said it out loud
before.
So, what's he done wrong? Nothing.
We'd never spent much time together
until recently.
And when we did, I began to wonder
how much we really had in common.
How recent was this time you spent
together?
VERY recent.
Are we talking about your so-called
sketching trip?
Because I never believed in that for
a moment.
The point is, I wasn't seeing him
clearly but now I do...
He's a nice man. A very nice man.
But not...
I mean, of course, we talked about
things.
But I think my judgement was rather
clouded by...
By what Miss Elinor Glyn likes to
write about in her novels.
Maybe.
But I seem to have got over that now.
Well, I won't ask how.
Please don't.
Well, I'll back you up if you
support me.
Are we talking about Miss Bunting or
your move to America?
I'm not sure. Either or both.
Well, you're asking a lot. I'm not
very keen on Miss Bunting
and I can't bear the thought of your
leaving.
Well, if you love me, you'll support
me.
Then I suppose I'll have to.
I was wondering about Rose's Russian
tea. Shall we go together?
Well, when is it?
This afternoon.
Oh, good heavens. I'd forgotten all
about it.
Well, I'm not sure I'll have the
energy. You must come.
You've been to Russia. None of us
have.
Did you get to know any when you
were there? Oh, yes.
Oh, yes.
Did you keep up with them?
Oh, I'm afraid not.
An unlucky friend is tiresome enough.
An unlucky acquaintance is
intolerable.
You're all heart!
We're back. Phew. I was terrified you
were going to miss it.
No, not likely. By the way, before I
left, I asked Pattinson
to look out the Russian things from
my father's visit. Did it happen?
Oh, it did. And they'll be so
thrilled.
If we're going to do it, we might as
well do it properly.
Don't you agree, Mrs Patmore?
Yes, M'Lord.
What's the matter with her? Nothing
for you to worry about.
I'm not but what is it? Something
beneath your Lordship's notice.
She'll get over it.
There's not nearly enough lemon.
Well, shall I go down and tell them?
No, I'll do it.
Tony, I don't believe it.
What's going on? Don't ask. Rose
wanted to invite Russians for tea.
And it's turned into a Jubilee
celebration.
How was London? How is it always?
Large and noisy.
Lady Grantham. Isobel.
Well, I wanted to see you. You've
spent a day in a car for that. Yes.
I didn't want to nag you over
the telephone when if I drove up
we could make our plans together.
Good afternoon, my dear.
Granny. Now, Granny, there's
something I'd love to show you.
Hello, Lord Gillingham. It's
very nice of you to come for this.
I came to see Mary, really.
Of course you did.
And so you should.
You were always very kind to me.
Mrs Crawley. Thank you.
I don't think I am. Yes, you are.
I appreciate it.
I'm sorry to add to your labours.
Don't worry, M'Lady.
I'll have them sliced in no time.
Daisy, are you ready? Daisy's busy
I'm afraid. I've got too much on.
Why? What's happening? There's a big
tea for the Russian refugees.
Your displaced Tsarist aristos. You
could always stay if you like.
Lots to eat.
I hope his arrival means you intend
to make it public.
Darling, granny, you know how much I
value your advice...
Which means you intend to ignore it.
I won't be hurried into anything.
Not by you or him.
But if you weren't certain, why on
earth did you go to bed with him?
Well, in my day...
a lady was incapable of feeling
physical attraction
until she had been instructed to do
so by her mama.
I don't believe that.
Seriously, my dear, you have to take
control of your feelings...
..before they take control of you.
Baxter...
M'Lady... I thought a lot about what
you told me yesterday.
And I still think you should report
Mr Coyle.
I won't, M'Lady. And if that makes a
difference...
It won't. You may stay.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Have you seen what we've dug out for
the Ruskies?
Well, I say, 'we', it was Pattinson
who did it.
Does it matter? You place no value
on my opinions.
Cora, I was cross. I had travelled
the length of England
to spend the evening with you and
you had gone out.
Aren't I allowed to be cross? Cross
but not unjust.
Would you excuse me? I think they're
here.
M'Lady. Mr Drewe is at the back door
downstairs.
He's asking for you. Should I ask
him to come up? No, I'll go down.
They told me you were here. I didn't
know you were entertaining.
It doesn't matter. What is it?
Tell me there's nothing wrong.
Please. There's nothing wrong with
Marigold.
Thank God. No. What's wrong is
Margie.
I know I've annoyed her. I'm afraid
you must stay away, M'Lady.
That's all. Not forever.
But for now, you must stay away.
M'Lady.
You have Russian connections, Miss
Bunting? No.
I'm here under false pretences.
Nonsense. You're welcome.
What is THAT woman doing here? Rose
found her in the kitchen
and asked her to join us. Why?
Don't be silly. She had to.
Why do you let her irritate you so?
How dare you say such things to me?!
I don't think she meant any... She
curses the name of our Holy Father.
The Tsar. I said he was misguided in
his policies.
No. No. I can't listen to this!
Lady Rose, would you please arrange
for us to return to York immediately.
Oh, but before you go, won't you
come and see the mementoes
of the wedding of Tsar Alexander
II's daughter?
Lord Grantham had them put out
especially for you to see.
You have Romanov's relics here?
My parents went to St Petersburg in
1874.
When Queen Victoria's son, Prince
Alfred,
married the Grand Duchess Maria.
Grand Duchess Maria.
Those words... They already make...
me weep. Oh, dear.
Oh, we can't have that.
Thank you.
Now do you see why she irritates me?
Tom, keep her under control.
She only wants...
I feel rather guilty. I thought
they'd enjoy the things we found.
Oh, dear, no. They ARE enjoying
them.
What were you doing in Russia?
Lord Grantham was in the household
of Prince Alfred.
And we went to St Petersburg for
their wedding.
I suppose it was very splendid.
Oh, you've no idea.
Receptions and balls. Glittering
parades.
Rides in a horse-drawn sleigh.
Flying across the snow at midnight.
Excuse me. Make way. Make way.
Oh. Oh, how funny.
I wondered what had happened to that
fan.
That wasn't given to your father. It
was given to me. Who by? The Tsar?
No. No. Not by the Tsar. No.
No, we were at a ball.
In the Winter Palace. And it was
so...
Oh, it was so hot. There were
icicles hanging outside the window.
But the rooms were as hot as the
tropics.
I was wearing pale blue velvet.
Trimmed with silver lace.
And when I gave you this fan you hid
it in your reticule
in case Lord Grantham should be
angry.
Good heavens.
I hope you can forgive me.
When I knew the others are coming, I
could not resist the temptation.
This is amazing. You know each other.
You met in St Petersburg?
We did.
Allow me...
to present my son, Lord Grantham.
Prince Kuragin.
I am flattered to be remembered.
How is the princess? Well, I hope.
I don't know.
Why don't we go back to the hall and
have some more tea?
Yes. Thank you.
Thank you.
Granny has a past.
Thank heavens Papa and Aunt Rosamund
were already born
or we could spin all sorts of fairy
tales.
How's it going? There seems to be a
good deal of emotion being vented
among the guests in the library but
then they are foreigners.
Right. Now, I must get on.
Stop giving me such knowing looks.
I met the prince when I was
travelling with your grandfather.
Nothing could be more respectable.
Whatever you say.
Away with your impertinent
conclusions!
My only conclusion is this -
I know you understand my predicament
far better than you let on.
Have you made plans to see your
admirer again?
Drive on.
I'm studying the Glorious Revolution
of 1688.
They'll be a glorious revolution
here if you don't watch!
I do hope this won't be something
you'll regret. I won't.
You only say that to sound clever.
I know. You should try it.
Good heavens. There's Charles Blake.
I think you know Lady Mary Crawley.
Miss Lane Fox.
We don't know each other exactly.
We know OF each other.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.